Guide to the Edward John Kempf Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS AND RESEARCH MATERIALS, 1911-1959; Series II; 7 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Bisexual Differentiation (1st draft)
    - Chapter XIV, "Sex Differences in Preadolescence,", undated (Box 13, Folder 151)
    - Chapter XIV, "Sexual Differentiation of the Preadolescent Attitude,", undated (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Chapter XV, "Puberty and its Psycho-Sexual and Physiological Differentiations,", undated (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Bisexual Differentiation (2nd draft)
    - Chapter XVI, "Post-Adolescent Psychosexual Differentiations. The Age of Homosexuality,", undated (Box 14, Folder 154)
    - Chapter XVII, "Age of Sexual Maturity of the Organism and Personality,", undated (Box 14, Folder 155)
    - Chapter XVII, "The Art of Making Love,", undated (Box 14, Folder 156)
    - Chapter XVIII, "Psychology of the Family,", undated (Box 14, Folder 157)
    - Chapter XIX, "Culture of Sex and Society,", undated (Box 14, Folder 158)
    - Chapter V, "Bisexual Gonads and Gonaducts,", undated (Box 14, Folder 159)
    - Chapter VI, "Gonadal Differentiation and Development of Sex Characters,", undated (Box 14, Folder 160)
    - Chapter X, "Protoplasm — The Self-Reproducing Organization of Autogenously and Exogenously Equilibrating, Bisensimotive, Reversible Bidynamic Aqueous Reaction Systems,", undated (Box 14, Folder 161)
    - Chapter XIII, "Bidynamic and Bisensimotive Differentiation in Equilibrating, Protoplasmic Reaction Systems,", undated (Box 14, Folder 162)
    - Chapter XVII, "Autonomic-Endocrine Bidynamic Internal and External Equilibrium,", undated (Box 14, Folder 163)
    - Chapter XXI, "Bisexual Internal and External Adaptability of the Autogenous Pressure of Energy,", undated (Box 14, Folder 164)
    - Chapter XXII, "Origin and Evolution of the Autonomic and Somatic Neuromuscular and Receptor Systems,", undated (Box 14, Folder 165)
    - Chapter XXV, "Physiopsychology of Autogenous Organization of Attitude,", undated (Box 14, Folder 166)
    - Chapter XXVI, "Psychophysiology of Organization of Attitude,", undated (Box 15, Folder 167)
    - Chapter XXVII, "Cardiovascular Emotivation of Autogenous, Counter-balancing Neuro-Cardiovascular, Hemodynamic Emotivation,", undated (Box 15, Folder 168)
    - Chapter XXVIII, "Autonomic Segmental Cravings Differentiating Attitudes,", undated (Box 15, Folder 169)
    - Chapter XIX, "Attitude Differentiation and Determination of Conditioning Reflexes,", undated (Box 15, Folder 170)
    - Chapter XXXII, "Attitude and Harmony, Contrast and Conflict in Conditioning Reflexes,", undated (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - Maturation of Man (1st draft)
    - Outline of the first draft of Maturation of Man, undated (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Chapter I, "Holistic Laws of Life,", undated (Box 16, Folder 173-174)
    - Summary of Chapters I and II, undated (Box 16, Folder 175)
    - Chapter IV, "Unorganized Energy" (Part 1), undated (Box 16, Folder 176)
    - Chapter IV, "Unorganized Energy" (Part 2), undated (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - Chapter IV, "Unorganized Energy" (Part 3), undated (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - Chapter VI, "Psychology of the Family and the Individual's Relation to It"(outline), undated (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - Chapter XXXIII, "The Origin of Language in the Magic of Special Vocal Sounds for Certain Things" (pp. 1-99), undated (Box 16, Folder 180)
    - Chapter XXXIII, "The Origin of Language in the Magic of Special Vocal Sounds for Certain Things" (pp. 100-174), undated (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - Chapter XXXIV, "Expressive, Repressive and Repressed Functioning with or without Insight of the Ego-Attitude,", undated (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Chapter XXXIV, "Repression and Substitution for Sublimation with Insight,", undated (Box 16, Folder 183)
    - "Theories of Evolution,", undated (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - Untitled chapter, undated (Box 16, Folder 185)
  - Maturation of Man (2nd draft)
    - "Introduction," Maturation of Man, undated (Box 17, Folder 186)
    - "Physiological Origins of Affectative Persons,", undated (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - "Postural Tensions,", undated (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - "Visceral Tensions,", undated (Box 17, Folder 189)
    - Evil Eye — Black Magic — White Magic, undated (Box 17, Folder 190)
    - "Culture of Self-Determining Egocentric Attitude Formation,", undated (Box 17, Folder 191)
    - "The Ego: Its Nature, Origin and Functions,", undated (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - Maturation of Man (3rd draft)
    - Outline of the third draft of Maturation of Man, undated (Box 17, Folder 193)
    - Chapter VI, "Thermo-Bidynamic Origin of Bisexual and Somatic Differentiation,", undated (Box 17, Folder 194)
    - Chapter XIV, "Basic Processes in Differentiation and Organization of the Organism,", undated (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - Chapter VII [?], "Comparative Animal Bisexual Reproductive and Somatic Differentiation,", undated (Box 17, Folder 196)
    - "Differentiation of Segmental and Systemic Autonomic Emotional Cravings,", undated (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - Miscellaneous Chapters and Notes
    - Chapter VI, "Autogenous Elemental and Environmental Fitness for Pyramiding Organization of Equilibrating Bisensimotive Bidynamics,", undated (Box 18, Folder 198)
    - "Electrolytic Life of Water,", undated (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - "Fundamentals of Physio-PsychoSociodynamics,", 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 200)
    - "How Science Knows What it Knows,", undated (Box 18, Folder 201)
    - "Introduction to" Attitude, undated (Box 18, Folder 202)
    - Chapter III, "Organization of Consciousness,", undated (Box 18, Folder 203)
    - "Sociogenic Mechanisms,", undated (Box 18, Folder 204)
    - "Sociogenic Attitudinal Counter-balancing Retroaction between Two, Three, Four, Five or More People" (pp. 70-173), undated (Box 18, Folder 205)
    - "Sociogenic Attitudinal Counter-balancing Retroaction between Two, Three, Four, Five or More People" (pp. 174-267), undated (Box 18, Folder 206)
    - "Respiratory Inhibition and Repression of Emotional Speech,", undated (Box 18, Folder 207)
    - "The Third or Enclosed Level of Holistic Electrodynamic Organization,", undated (Box 18, Folder 208)
    - Notes on Freud, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 209)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1930, 1937-1938, undated (Box 18, Folder 210-211)
- PERSONAL, Series III; 0.25; (1 box)
  The PERSONAL series consists of biographical material and memorabilia.
  - Autobiographical notes (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - Biographical material (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - List of publications of Edward J. Kempf (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - Membership certificates (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - Programs from conferences (Box 19, Folder 216)